BENSON GATHU

①+254 703 446950 🖅 bensongathu23@gmail.com

PROFILE

ICT Graduate committed to supporting digital transformation aligned to an organization's objectives. Experienced in designing project life cycle, ensuring end users enjoy the efficiency of systems and implementing IT strategies. Accustomed to maintaining and monitoring networking and computer systems, testing and evaluating new technologies and installation of ICT software and hardware. Professional skills include:

- Able to easily adapt to new software and systems
- Collaborative team player
- Communication skills gained through project documentation
- Problem solving
- Able to effectively organize tasks

Technical skills

- Python
- Django
- Flask
- Angular
- JQuery
- MySql

- PostareSal
- Linux commands
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript/Typescript
- Bootstrap
- Web Design

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Information Technology | JKUAT | 2016 - 2019

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education | Kijabe Boys High School | 2011 - 2014

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Fullstack Development | Moringa School | Mar - Aug 2021

Cyber Security Program | Kenya Education Network | Oct – Nov2019

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer (Intern) | Eco-Architecture and Built Limited | Oct 2021 - Apr 2022

- Resourceful in coding python scripts, reviewed code for other engineers, debugged software applications and tested design elements
- Productively engaged in troubleshooting, debugging, installation, upgrading and customization of existing software
- Proactively learnt about new technologies in relation to their relevance in the field

IT Intern | Mount Kenya University | Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

- Monitored systems in operation and input commands to troubleshoot areas such as biometric registration
- Updated and digitized records and systems
- Set up functional workstations for teams by configuring hardware, devices and software

Benson Gathu Page | 1

Intern | National Hospital Insurance Fund | Aug - Nov 2018

- Gained hands on experience in supporting a national service by working with teams to ensure sound ICT strategies were implemented
- o Practiced software and hardware installations, while supporting end users in embracing new technologies
- Polished problem-solving skills through troubleshooting, diagnosing and resolving computer and network issues
- Successfully created, installed and maintained the network system

Project Portfolio (Sample)

- School Management System | System used to keep records and manage students in a school
- Password Locker Script | A script code that enables users manage all passwords
- o Instagram Clone | App that enables people share and interact with images (similar to Instagram
- Tours & Travel booking System | Web based system that enables people to see and book upcoming tours

Other Projects:

Portfolio | https://gportfolio96.herokuapp.com/

GitHub | https://github.com/BensonGathu

REFERENCES

Mary Wanjiku Njoroge

Director,

Eco-Architecture and Built Limited,

Cell: +254 712 229841 | Email: Mshiku17@gmail.com

Christine Karimi

Technical Mentor, Moringa School

Email: christine.karimi@moringaschool.com

Florence Mbugua

Human Resource Manager,

NHIF, Ruiru

Cell: +254 722 838119

Benson Gathu Page | 2